Konstance Smith 1078 Willow Avenue Canton, MS 39046 (601) 859-1167 or (601) 540-7221

Dear Prospective Employer,

Enclosed is a copy of my resume for your review in reference to the position with in the administration. Please consider my application with regards to the qualifications outlined in my resume.

I am a graduate of Hinds Community College with an Associates Degree in Applied Science. I am currently enrolled at Colorado Technical University Online in the Bachelor's of Administration Program with a concentration in Human Resource Management. Recently, I have obtained certificates from CTU Online in the Basic Fundamentals of Business, December 2009 and Project Planning, February 2010. I anticipate completing the bachelor's program in November 2010. I have excellent leadership and customer service skills. Throughout my educational studies and employment history, I have strived to provide the best quality service to the companies that I have worked for as well as the clients served.

I have worked in Public Assistance Services for 4 years and I am very confident that my skills and experience will be beneficial to this administration. Over the years, I have worked in many different areas and have mastered many tasks and I welcome this opportunity to become apart of your team. I would like the opportunity to discuss my qualifications with you in person. If you need to reach me, feel free to call. Please leave a message if I am not available and I will return your call as soon as possible.

Thank you for your attention and consideration. I am looking forward to talking with you.

Sincerely,

Konstance Smith

Konstance Smith 1078 Willow Avenue Canton, MS 39046 (601) 859-1167 or (601) 540-7221 ckonstance@yahoo.com

Career objective

To obtain a challenging position within your administration with an opportunity for advancement.

Education

Hinds Community College Associate Degree in Applied Science Colorado Technical University

Professional Experience

Madison County Citizens Services Agency (MCCSA), 152 Watford Drive, Canton, MS 39046, Program Manager/Coordinator, February 2007 - July 1, 2009.

- Leads the technical side of all programs, managing and defining the functional specifications and defining how the programs/grants will work as they relate to Madison County.
- Works with various program managers within the state to improve MCCSA's processes and strategies.
- Works closely with leaders (federal and state) to assist with the development and implementation of new programs.
- Monitors all programs for consistencies and insuring that programs/grants follows guidelines set up by the county, state and federal agencies.
- Monitor monthly CMPDD reports, LIHEAP vendor's payments, reports, leveraging reports and other necessary reports.
- Ensures maintenance of agency's LIHEAP records.
- Assist the Executive Director with payments reports, proposals, grant preparation and modifications.
- Supervise employees associated with CMPDD Grants and monitor daily attendance of all employees.
- Prepare monthly attendance logs to assist with payroll.
- Assist Human Resource Manager of Madison County with new hires and information documentation.

Accomplishments at MCCSA

- Responsible for the success of the yearly audit reports for over 2 years for the CMPDD Grants for all grants provided for Madison County's elderly citizens.
- Responsible for the success of the yearly audit and reporting of the LIHEAP Grant for more than 2 years provided by the MS Department of Human Services for Energy Assistance.

Madison County Economic Development Authority, 140 Peace Street, Canton, MS 39046 Administrative Assistance, September 2006 - February 2007.

- Organizing county documents and reporting documents for yearly audits and review.
- Ordering monthly supplies and maintaining records of all transactions.
- Implementations of Board Members Reporting documents books for meetings conducted on a monthly basis
- Responsible for ordering supplies for the facility
- Customer Service Representative: Responsible for communicating with Board Members for meetings and social events.
- Assisting the Executive Director and Finance Manager with board presentations.

Mississippi Department of Employment Security, 152 Watford Drive, Canton, MS 39046, Employment Representative III - July 2005 - August 2006

- Interview applicants to determine occupational qualifications for placement.
- Market job placement services to employers.
- Provide information of services that the MDES offers.
- Maintain files, records and meet job placement needs for employers.
- Support staff with WIA, TAA, Unemployment Insurances and Department of Labor requirements and eligibility protocol.

H& R Block, 154 West Center Street, Canton, MS 39046, Tax Preparer, December 2004 – May 2006

- Prepare taxes, sale retirement investment accounts and mortgage brokerage packages to clients.
- Ensure deposits, and automatic bank transactions along with accounts payable records.
- Assist Office Manager with maintenance of office equipment.
- Customer Services and Receptionist of clients seeking services provided by H&R Block.

Mississippi Department of Health, 570 East Woodrow Wilson, Jackson MS 39046, Data Entry Clerk III Vital Records – September 2002 - September 2007

- Data entry, perform daily review of mail for corrections to birth records, marriage and birth certificates.
- File Document and birth records for child support decrees
- Number and catalog records for birth, marriage, divorce and death certificates.

Canton High School, 634 Finney Road, Canton, MS 39046, Substitute Teacher, September 1998 – September 2002

- Provide Daily assistance to facility, staff and students.
- Maintain records for grades and absentees.
- Maintain order and administer assignments in the absence of the instructor.

Jackson Hinds Comprehensive Health Center, 3502 West Northside Drive., Jackson, MS 39213, Medical Laboratory Technician, May 1991 – March 1996

- Processed laboratory specimens for chemistry, hematology, urinalysis and specialized testing.
- Maintain records for clinical monthly calculations of quality
- Instructed and trained medical students in the basic fundamentals of laboratory concepts and technologies.

References available upon request.